Sasha Prokhorenko

+49 7431 5492351 | <u>djminikin@gmail.com</u>| <u>http://minikin.me/</u>|skype: minikin.robotek

Professional Summary

Forward thinking & awarded iOS & IoT software engineer +6 years of development & delivery IoT projects for high-profile clients +3 years of experience in iOS development Solid understanding of the full IoT and mobile development life cycle Able to meet tight deadlines and delivers superior performance Passionate about learning and trying new technologies

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (IOS / IOT), MEEETNOW GMBH — JULY 2016-PRESENT

- Delivered, developed & supported multiple iOS apps for business clients in tight deadlines
- IoT stack development for embedded devices (MQTT, IBM Bluemix IoT...)
- Proposed and implemented new methods for iOS development
- Web interfaces development with React & Redux

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (IOS / IOT / R&D), MINIKIN.ME - 2014-PRESENT

- Shipped apps for clients & own apps to the App Store
- Delivered & developed IoT projects (software & hardware) from scratch for clients
- R&D consulting for clients
- Backend infrastructure development, maintaining and REST API's integration with Parse, IBM Bluemix, Firebase and Realm.

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT DIRECTOR (IOS / IOT / WEB), AIMBULANCE — 2010-2016

Awarded the most effective digital agency in Ukraine.

- Delivered & developed IoT projects (software & hardware) from scratch for big clients,
- Responsible for R&D that expanded company technologies,
- iOS development : architected and implemented client/server application with Parse and Facebook integration,
- Optimised web production process & minimised risks,
- Supervised project production processes and coordinating software developers
- Technical consulting.

PROJECT MANAGER / PRODUCT OWNER, BRAINBERRY — 2007-2010

Digital agency which provides complex digital campaigns for high-profile clients & launched a few start-ups.

- Delivered multiple websites for clients,
- Launched several web start-ups,
- Coordinating and monitoring work of software developers and third parties,

Skills

Swift - IoT Stack - Objective-C - iOS SDK - Cocoa- Xcode - CocoaPods - Realm - Couchbase - CoreData - Mobile Iron - MQTT - Node - Python - REST - JSON - JS - CSS - HTML - WebSockets - Ubuntu/Debian - Git -Travis - Sketch

Education

National Mining University, Dnipropetrovsk (Ukraine) — Master of Engineering, 2002 - Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians.